目前我们必须跳入修复
currently we have to jump into fix
并手动启动我们的顶级主管
and manually start our top level supervisor
是的
yeah instead
我们希望主管自动启动
we'd like the supervisor to start automatically
当应用程序本身启动时
when the application itself starts
所以当应用程序启动时
so when the application starts
我们如何让它运行这行代码
how do we get it to run this line of code
它开始了我们的顶级主管
it starts our top level supervisor
点燃一切
which fires everything up
但要回答我们的问题，我们需要退后一步
but to answer our question we need to take a step back
到这一点
up to this point
我们一直在相当松散地使用术语应用程序
we've been using the term application fairly loosely
但应用程序是一流的顶级实体
but an application is a first class top entity
一直以来
and all along
我们一直在应用程序的上下文中工作
we've been working in the context of an to application
让我们看看幕后发生了什么
let's see what's been going on behind the scenes
第一个我要离开ix
1st I'm going to get out of ix
我只是要清理所有构建工件
and I'm just going to clean up all the build artifacts
所有编译的代码
all the compiled code
通过使用混合清洁
by using mix clean
好吧，如果我使用混合编译
okay then if I use mix compile
虽然我们看到它编译成 20 个文件
while we see it compiled to 20 files
然后它说生成
and then it said generated
以同样的方式奴役
servile in the same way
如果我要再次清理一切
if I were to clean up everything again
并进入 ix 会话
and jump into an ix session
好吧，它会自动编译所有内容
well it automatically compiles everything
编译20个文件，它还说生成
compiling 20 files and it also says generated
服务应用
servi app
现在我们回到哪里
now we'll come back to where
该应用程序在一分钟内生成
the app got generated in a minute
第一的
first
让我们看看当前正在运行哪些应用程序
let's see which applications are currently running
为此，我们可以使用应用程序模块
to do that we can use the application module
还有一个叫做启动应用程序的功能
and there's a function called started applications
嗯，这很有趣
well this is pretty interesting
我们看到我们的调查应用程序是一个正在运行的应用程序
we see that our survey app is a running application
以及许多其他应用程序，包括
along with a bunch of other applications including
毒药是一种外部依赖
poison which is an external dependency
我们在课程的前面添加了
we added earlier in the course
现在
now
毒启动了它需要的其他一些应用程序
poison started a few other applications that it needed
包括ssl
including ssl
和公钥和密码
and public key and crypt
我们甚至看到了长生不老药
and we even see elixir
和混合和性和标准的lib和上校
and mix and sex and standard lib and colonel
这些都是当前正在运行的应用程序
those are all currently running applications
所以叫 ix
so calling ix
短跑
dash
s mix 自动启动调查应用程序
s mix automatically started the survey application
及其所有依赖项
and all of its dependencies which are
也应用
also applications
但它怎么知道要做这一切
but how did it know to do all that
好吧，这让我们回到了混音圈
well this brings us full circle back to the mix
ex文件是
ex file that is
调查顶级目录的正下方
right underneath the survey top level directory
你会记得
you'll remember
当我们生成这个文件时
that this file got generated when we
创建了项目
created the project
使用混合新
using mix new
在项目功能中，我们看到应用程序名称
and in the project function we see the application name
调查版本号
survey also the version number
然后它调用
and then it calls the
获取外部依赖的深度函数
depth function to get external dependencies
在那里
and down there
我们添加了毒药作为外部依赖项
we added poison as an external dependency
在课程的早期
earlier on in the course
毒药本身就是一种应用
and poison is an application in its own right
然后我们也有这个应用功能
and then we also have this application function
描述应用程序的
that describes the application
我们看到毒应用是自动的
we saw that the poison application was automatically
开始，因为它被列为依赖项
started because it's listed as a dependency
并混合推断
and mix infers
从什么开始
what to start
然后我们可以使用这个额外的应用程序来启动
and then we can use this extra applications to start
包含的任何额外应用程序
any extra applications that are included
或早早与长生不老药一起发货
or shipped with elixir early
例如
for example
默认情况下，记录器应用程序已启动
by default the logger application is started
所以这个文件中的所有信息都用于生成
so all the information in this file is used to generate
调查申请
the survey application
那么生成的调查申请文件在哪里
so where is the generated survey application file
我是
I'm
在顶级的常规终端会话中
in a regular terminal session here in the top level
调查目录
survey directory
并且所有构建工件都存在于
and all the build artifacts live in the
下划线构建目录
underscore build directory
现在，一旦我们进入这个目录，我们就在耳林
now once we go into this directory we're in earlingland
所以结构感觉有点正统
so the structure feels a bit on orthodox
给长生不老药开发者
to an elixir developer
但它遵循 top 预期的约定
but it follows the conventions expected by top
和伯爵vm
and the earling vm
所以根据法案
so under the bill
目录有两个子目录
directory there are two sub directories
开发和测试，所以我要深入开发
dev and test so I'm going to go down into dev
然后它下面有两个子目录
then there are two sub directories under it
合并不用担心
consolidated don't worry about it
然后生活，我们要去那里
and then live we're going to go down there
然后在 lib 下我们看到两个子目录
and then under lib we see two sub directories
毒药和调查
poison and survey
这是两个应用程序
those are the two applications
让我们进入调查子目录
let's go into the survey sub directory
然后是合并的将忽略
and then there's consolidated which will ignore
而最重要的部分是e bin目录
and the most important part is the e bin directory
那么里面有什么
so what's inside of there
好吧，它包括一堆以结尾的文件
well it includes a bunch of files ending in
对应于我们每个模块的梁
beam that correspond to each of our modules
这些是运行的编译二进制文件
these are compiled binary files that run
在伯爵vim上
on the earling vim
在编译期间
during compilation
我们 lib 目录中的所有文件都已编译
all the files in our lib directory were compiled
并且产生的光束小瓶最终在这个目录中
and the resulting beam vials ended up in this directory
但如果你看底部
but if you look at the bottom
请注意，还有一个调查点应用程序文件
notice that there's also a survey dot app file
这是一个纯文本文件
it's a plain text file
所以让我们继续看看里面有什么
so let's go ahead and see what's inside
我只是要使用 cat 命令来做到这一点
and I'm just going to use the cat command to do that
它只是要打印出该文件中的内容
it's just going to print out what's in that file
服务点应用程序
servey dot app
和
and
我会把它缩小，这样我们就可以看到这里的一切
I'll just shrink it down so we can see everything here
有趣的是，这是伯爵代码
well interestingly it's earling code
这只是这里的一个大伯爵倒塌
this is just one big earling topple right here
它包括应用程序名称调查
it includes the application name survey
有一个描述调查
there's a description survey
我们看到有一个版本号
we see that there's a version number
在那里
right there
它还有一个已编译模块的列表，这里是列表
it also has a list of compiled modules here's the list
每个模块对应一个梁文件
and each of those modules corresponds to a beam file
然后还有一个应用程序列表
and then there's also a list of applications
所以我们看到了毒应用记录器
so we see the poison application logger
接着
and then
上校的标准唇膏和长生不老药也在混合物中
also colonel's standard lip and elixir were in the mix
所以你可以想到这个
so you can think of this
作为定义服务应用程序的规范
as a specification that defines the service application
这个文件是由 mix 自动生成的
this file was automatically generated by mix
部分是通过使用混合中的信息
in part by using information that's in the mix
我们之前看过的多余文件
excess file we looked at earlier
现在好消息是我们永远不必碰这个文件
now the good news is we never have to touch this file
它是为我们生成的
it's generated for us
好吧，让我们为我们的应用程序添加一个更好的描述
well let's add a better description of our application
让我们称它为一个不起眼的 http 服务器
let's call it a humble http server
是的，我们只是回到我们的混音前
yes we just come back over to our mix ex
我们可以在项目下添加一个描述键
and we can add a description key under project
一个不起眼的 http 服务器
a humble http server
把它存起来
save that away
现在回到这里
now back over here
我在我的顶级调查目录中
I'm in my top level survey directory
如果我使用混合编译
if I use mix compile
然后我们再次查看该服务应用程序
and then we look at that service app again
好吧，您注意到描述发生了变化
well you notice the descriptions changed
它现在是一个不起眼的臀部服务器
it's now a humble hip server
所以服务点应用程序文件得到了更新
so the service dot app file got updated
当我们运行混合编译时
when we ran mixed compile
现在我们看到了构建目录
now we saw that the build directory
也有毒应用
also had the poison app
让我们来看看
so let's take a look at that
它正在建设中
it's under build
它处于开发库毒药之下
and it's under dev lib poison
我们想进入e bin目录
and we want to go down into e bin directory for it
好
well
你会看到只有一堆梁文件
and you see that there's just a bunch of beam files
对应所有模块
corresponding to all the modules
在毒药库里
that are in the poison library
还有一个毒点应用文件
and there's also a poison dot app file
看起来很熟悉
looks pretty familiar
让我们看看
let's have a look at that
毒坚果应用程序，我将运行
poison nut app and I'm just going to run the
cat 命令就可以了
cat command on it
把它缩小一点
shrink it down a little bit
所以我们可以看到完整的东西
so we can see the full thing
好吧，它有一个描述，包含所有模块
well it's got a description has all the modules
它有一个版本号
it's got a version number
然后启动它需要的应用程序
and then the applications that it needs started
所以当我们启动 if s mix 时，它会编译
so when we fire up if s mix it compiles
一切过时的东西
everything that's out of date
生成一个新的服务文件
generates a new service file
然后 top 查找服务文件
and then top looks for the service file
并使用它来启动应用程序
and uses it to start the application
及其所有依赖项
and all of its dependencies
包括我们在这里看到的毒药
including poison we see right here
回到 ix
back over an ix
我们也可以将应用程序作为一个洞来停止
we can also stop the application as a hole
然后重新开始
and then start it again
所以我们可以使用那个应用程序模块
so we can use that application module
我们可以叫停
we can call stop
在我们的调查申请中
on our survey application
好吧，如果我们再次查看已启动的应用程序
okay now if we look at started applications again
好吧，您注意到servi不在顶部
well you notice servi isn't at the top
所以我们可以通过使用 start pass serve 重新启动它
so we could restart it by using start passing serve
现在又开始了
and now it started again
所以这里的外卖
so the takeaway here
是顶级应用程序是一流的实体吗
is that an top application is a first class entity
可以作为一个单元启动和停止
that can be started and stopped as a unit as
一个整体，可以在其他系统中重用
a whole and can be reused in other systems
这样它更像是一个组件
in this way it's more like a component
或服务而不是传统应用程序
or a service than a traditional application
所以现在我们有了更好的
so now that we have a better
了解什么是顶级应用程序
understanding of what an top application is
让我们回到最初的目标
let's return to our original goal
即使我们的应用程序正在运行
even though our application is running
我们仍然需要手动启动主管
we still have to start the supervisor manually to
引导一切
bootstrap everything
而不是手动启动主管
instead of manually starting the supervisor
我们希望主管自动启动
we want the supervisor to start automatically
当应用程序本身启动时
when the application itself starts
那么我们通常如何告诉 top 做某事
so how do we typically tell top to do something
特定于我们的应用程序
that specific to our application
好吧，我们使用回调
well we use a callback
我们使用回调来专门处理性别行为
we've used callbacks to specialize gendered behaviors
我们用过
and we've used
回调以专门化主管行为
callbacks to specialize supervisor behaviors
以同样的方式
in the same way
我们将使用回调来专门化
we'll use a callback to specialize
应用行为
the application behavior
因为回调模块将使用此文件调查
as the callback module will use this file survey
ex它在lib下
ex it's under lib
但它不在调查子目录中
but it's not in the survey sub directory
这是我们运行时生成的顶级文件
it's this top level file that was generated when we ran
混新长
mix new a long
很久以前
long time ago
所以我们将在这里摆脱这些你好东西
so we'll get rid of this hello stuff here
然后我们将使用应用程序行为
and then we're going to use the application behavior
并且应用程序行为需要回调
and the application behavior expects the callback
定义启动函数的模块
module to define a start function
start 函数有两个参数
start function takes two arguments
第一个将是类型
the first one is going to be the type
现在这通常只是原子
now this is typically just the atom
正常，所以我们将忽略它
normal so we're going to ignore that
第二个是参数
and the second one is arguments
我们也将忽略这些
and we're going to ignore those as well
然后我们要打印出来
then we're going to print out
启动应用程序
starting the application
所以这个启动函数将被调用
so this start function will be invoked
应用程序启动时
when the application starts
我们想做什么
what do we want to do
好吧，我们想开始我们的顶级主管
well we want to start our top level supervisor
我碰巧放弃了
and I happen to have that quit
我只是将它粘贴在那里
I'm just going to paste it right in there
在开始时必须返回一个元组
in start must return a tuple
好的 pid 其中 pid 标识主管进程
okay pid where pid identifies the supervisor process
所以我们可以这样
so we can leave it like this
或者我们可以删除它
or we can just remove this
因为我们知道一个元组会被返回
because we know that a tuple is going to get returned
然后将隐式返回
and then that will be implicitly returned
通过启动功能
by the start function
这符合我们的讨价还价
which fulfills our side of the bargain
所以通过编写这个应用程序行为
so by writing this application behavior
我们基本上想覆盖
we basically want to override
应用程序的通用应用程序行为
the generic application behavior for the application
为此，我们需要确保
and to do that we need to make sure
这个调查模块被称为
that this survey module is called
我们在 mix ex 中做到这一点
and we do that in mix ex
在这个应用程序部分
down in this application section
我们将在这里添加一个新行
we're going to add a new line here
这将是mod
it's going to be mod
mod 指定要调用的回调模块
and mod specifies that callback module to invoke
应用程序启动时
when the application is started
我们给它一个元组，然后我们给它模块
we give it a tuple and then we give it the module
民意调查
survey
top 将调用该模块的启动函数
and top will invoke the start function of that module
这是合同的一部分
that's part of the contract
我们可以把它抹布
and we can pass it rag
我们将使用一个空列表
and we're just going to use an empty list
但你可以通过任何你需要的论点
but you could pass whatever argument you need
回调模块可以是
the callback module can be
任何使用应用程序行为的模块
any module that uses the application behavior
所以你可以创建一个新的
so you could have created a new
例如调查应用模块
survey application module for example
但也很常见只是使用它
but it's also common just to use this
顶层模块调查
top level module survey
这里的要点是 top 会自动调用
the takeaway here is that top will automatically call
该模块启动功能
this module start function
当它启动应用程序时
when it starts the application
所以我们会把它保存起来
so we'll save that away
然后我们想开始一个新的性爱会话
and then we want to start a new sex session
看看那个
and look at that
这次它点燃了一切
this time it fires everything up
它启动了应用程序
it started the application
然后它开始了我们的顶级主管
then it started our top level supervisor
然后其他一切都到位
and then everything else fell in place
现在如果你想启动应用程序怎么办
now what if you wanted to start the application
没有性外壳
without the sex shell
那么你可以使用混合运行
well you could use mix run
是的，如果你运行 mix run 我就离开这里
yeah I'll just get out of here if you run mix run
像那样
like that
它启动了一切
and it starts everything up
但是我们最终回到终端会话提示中
but then we end up back in a terminal session prompt
那是因为实例
well that's because the instance
我们的服务一经终止
terminated as soon as our service
启动功能完成
start function finished
顶级主管启动后
after the top level supervisor started
所以为了让它继续运行，我们需要使用它
so to keep it running we need to use this
没有暂停选项
no halt option
没有破折号
no dash halt
完美的
perfect
看到该输出提醒我我们的网络服务器
seeing that output reminds me that our web server
始终在端口 4000 上运行
always runs on port 4000
是的，端口号目前很难
yeah the port number is currently hard
在我们的 kickstarter 模块中编码
coded in our kickstarter module
所以在这里接受调查
so over here under survey
那里是kickstarter
there it is kickstarter
然后在这里我们在端口 4000 上启动它
and then down here we're starting it on port 4000
我们可以让这更容易配置
we can make this easier to configure
通过添加默认端口值
by adding a default port value
到应用环境
to the applications environment
为此，我们回到我们的 mix ex 文件
to do that we come back over to our mix ex file
然后我们将添加
and then we'll add
另一条线在这里申请
another line down here under application
它将结束，然后我们给它一个关键字列表
it's going to be end and then we give it a keyword list
所以我们的港口
so our port
我们想成为 3000 我将使用 3000
we want to be 3000 I'm going to use 3000
只是为了让你看到它从 4000 变化
just so that you see it changes from 4000
所以这要做的是添加这个键值对
so what this is going to do is add this key value pair
到应用环境
to the applications environment
所以让我们把它保存起来
so let's save this away
然后回到这里
then back over here
我要杀了性，我要使用混合编译
I'm going to kill sex and I'm going to use mix compile
这将生成一个新的服务应用程序文件
that's going to generate a new service app file
如果我们看看
and if we have a look at that
我们会注意到端口 3000 是
we'll notice that the port 3000 is part of
这个申请文件
this application file
所以现在当 top 启动应用程序时
so now when top starts the application
默认应用环境
the default application environment
将包括端口
will include the port
然后回来踢起动器
then back over and kick starter
而不是硬涂层端口
rather than hard coating the port
我们可以从应用程序的环境中读取它
we can read it from the application's environment
是的
yeah
我们这样做的方式是使用应用程序模块
the way we do that is we use the application module
有一个函数得到结束
there's a function get end
在这种情况下，我们将应用程序的名称传递给它
we pass it the application's name serving in this case
以及端口的变量名称
and the name of the variable which is port
然后我们可以在这里使用那个端口变量
then we can just use that port variable right down here
现在当我们启动 ix s mix
and now when we fire up ix s mix
你注意到了
well you notice
我们的网络服务器现在监听端口 3000
our web servers now listening on port 3000
很酷，现在我们有一个完整的
pretty cool now that we have a complete
正确的顶级应用程序运行
proper top application running
让我们看看观察者粘糊糊的样子
let's see what it looks like in the observer gooey
是的，让我们开火吧
yeah let's fire that up
在我们看过的课程的早些时候
earlier on in the course we looked at
单个进程正在运行
the individual process is running by going
进入此进程选项卡
into this processes tab
但现在我们可以转到应用程序选项卡
but now we can go to the applications tab
并查看所有应用程序
and see all the applications that
当前正在运行
are currently running
它在这里的左侧结束了
it's over on the left hand side here
包括我们不起眼的小调查应用程序
including our humble little survey application
所以让我们先来看看性应用程序
so let's start by having a look at the sex application
好吧，这很有趣，我们看到了它的监督树
well this is interesting we see its supervision tree
它有一个主管，然后它有
it has a supervisor and then it has
这里有两台服务器
two gen servers here
我们现在确切地知道它是如何工作的
and we now know exactly how that works
是的，如果我们看看上校
yeah if we look at colonel
好吧，它有一个主管
well it has a supervisor
上校 sup 就是它的名字
colonel sup is what it's named
然后注意到它有一个二级主管
and then notice it's got a second level supervisor
安全上校
colonel safe sup
然后这里有一些流程
and then it has some processes under here
所以这是它的监督树
so this is its supervision tree
如果我们看一下记录器
if we look at logger
好吧，它有一个顶级水平
well it's got a top level
监督者，然后它有一个观察者监督者
supervisor and then it's got a watcher supervisor
然后它有一些工作进程
and then it's got some worker processes
现在是大揭秘
and now for the big reveal
这是我们的监督树
here's our supervision tree
我们有顶级主管
we've got our top level supervisor
我们有我们的kickstarter
we've got our kickstarter
我们的第二级服务主管
our services supervisor that's our 2nd level
然后他们在管理孩子
and then they're managing children
好的
okay
让我们看看当我们杀死一个工作进程时会发生什么
let's see what happens when we kill a worker process
比如质押服务器
such as the pledge server
好的，如果我们点击它
okay if we click on that
我们看到这里现在是 1 点 69 分
we see down here it's pied one sixty nine currently
所以我可以右键单击它
so I can right click on it
杀死进程发送它来杀死信号
kill process send it to kill signal
好的，我们在这里看到
okay we see down here
启动质押服务器
starting the pledge server
所以它被我们的服务主管重新启动
so it got restarted by our services supervisor
如果我现在点击质押服务器
and if I click on pledge server now
好吧，它是一个不同的 pid 现在它是 4 6 6
well it's a different pid now it's 4 6 6
哦，这很酷
oh that's pretty cool
如果我们杀死服务主管会发生什么
what happens if we kill the services supervisor though
如果我们现在点击它，它就是一号坑六十八号
if we click on it right now it's pit one sixty eight
我们会以同样的方式杀死它
we'll kill it the same way
好吧，我们看到了
all right we see
服务主管正在重新启动
the services supervisor is getting restarted
启动了质押服务器
which started the pledge server
和传感器服务器
and the sensor server
如果我们点击 services supervisor 它的坑现在
and if we click on services supervisor its pit is now
4 7 4 太甜了
4 7 4 that's pretty sweet
这就是本课程的总结
that wraps it up for this course
非常感谢您加入我们
thanks so much for joining us
我们希望你玩得开心
we hope you have a lot of fun
使用图片构建您自己的应用程序
using a picture to build your own apps
我们下次见
we'll see you next time
现在让我们去拍摄一些熊
now let's go photograph some bears
甚至可能是野人
or maybe even sasquatch